National Women's Health Network records SSC.MS.00360
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. MEMBERSHIP AND FINANCIAL MATERIALS, 1977-2006
  The Financial materials include information directly related to fundraising and the financial aspects of the Network. There are budgets; development director correspondence; donations and gifts; financial statements and reports to the Board; correspondence and reports from fundraising consultants, contract employees and auditors; and grant materials. The Grant section contains rejection and support letters, grant plans and prospects, plus files on granting organizations and specific projects for which grant funds were requested. There are also materials regarding loans and miscellaneous fundraisers including the 10th anniversary of Our Bodies, Ourselves and related to eleven organizations regarding fundraising and philanthropy. Finally there are tax returns and fundraising trip and meetings materials.
  - Membership
    - Appeals
      - Sample and form letters, 1986, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Seasonal
        - Year end, 1997-99 (Box 30, Folder 2-4)
        - Summer, fall, and year end, 2000-01 (Box 30, Folder 5-8)
        - Spring, summer, winter, and year end, 2002 (Box 30, Folder 9-11)
        - Spring, fall, winter, and year end, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 12-14)
        - Spring and fall, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 15-16)
      - Special
        - Fundraising, 1984-87 (Box 30, Folder 17)
        - Hormone replacement therapy, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 18)
        - Member survey, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 19)
        - Membership renewal, 1984, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1)
          [see also Renewals]
        - Special appeal statistics, 1985-89 (Box 31, Folder 2)
        - Miscellaneous, 1979-2000 (Box 31, Folder 3-12)
    - Certificates, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Data base, 2004-2006, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Direct mail
      - Acquisition (new member) strategies
        - Analysis and planning, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 3)
        - Interviews, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 4)
        - Letters, 1991-99 (Box 32, Folder 5)
        - List ideas, 2001-2005 (Box 32, Folder 6)
        - New prospect package, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 7)
        - Reinstatement, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 8)
        - Summary results, 1987-89 (Box 32, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous, 1999-2005 (Box 32, Folder 10-16)
      - Campaigns, 1980-2001 (Box 33, Folder 1-17)
      - Consultants
        - A.B. Data, Ltd, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - Barbara Dana Associates, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 2)
        - Broder Associates, 1981-83 (Box 34, Folder 3)
        - Craver, Mathews, Smith & Co, 1979-84 (Box 34, Folder 4-6)
        - Creative Processing Systems, 1984-86 (Box 34, Folder 7)
        - EU Services, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 8)
        - Executive Systems, Inc., 1987-88 (Box 34, Folder 9)
        - Hamilton, Pat, 1994-95 (Box 34, Folder 10)
        - National Demographics & Lifestyles Inc., Customer Profile Analysis, 1988 2 P.J. Promotions, Inc., 1984 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - Interesting direct mail letters, 1982, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous
          - 1980-81 (Box 35, Folder 4-7)
          - 1982-83 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
      - Mailing list exchange, 1982-83 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Reports, 1980-95 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1984-85, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Gift memberships, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Members by state, 1996-2000 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Membership analysis, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Membership development grant, 1999-2000 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Membership Identity Project, 1999 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Membership manual, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Planning, 2000-06 (Box 37, Folder 1-5)
    - Procedures, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Renewals
      - Non-renewal questionnaires, 1980-82, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 7-10)
      - Problems, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 37, Folder 12-16)
      - Revisions, 1997-2002 (Box 38, Folder 1-5)
      - Telephone Reinstatements Program, 1982-83 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Reports to the board, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Surveys, 1983-98 (Box 38, Folder 8-9)
    - Telemarketing, 1988-95 (Box 38, Folder 10-12)
  - Financial materials
    - Budgets, 1977-2004 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      [see also SERIES II. ADMINISTRATION - Board of Directors Meetings]
    - Development director, correspondence, 1986-88 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Donation Processing Guide, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Deferred giving, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Donations and gifts
      - To NWHN
        - Freedman donation, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - Gift letters, 1982-83 (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - In-kind, 1985-88 (Box 39, Folder 4)
        - Matching gifts, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 5)
        - Memorial gifts, 1984-89 (Box 39, Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous, 1986-96, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - From NWHN, 1982-83 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Employment deduction programs, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Financial reports to the board, 1982-83 (Box 39, Folder 10-11)
    - Financial statements, 1979-2006 (Box 39, Folder 12-13)
    - Fundraising
      - Consultants, contract employees, auditors
        - Avalon Consulting Group, 1997-2000 (Box 39, Folder 14)
        - Etwaroo, Rudolph, 1981-83 (Box 39, Folder 15)
        - Fazio International, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 16)
        - Herzog Swayze, Inc. 1997 (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - Miscellaneous, 1983-94 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Corporate, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Grants
        - Correspondence
          - Rejection letter, 1978-85 (Box 40, Folder 4)
          - Support letters, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 5)
        - Foundation Fundraising Plan, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 6)
        - Foundation prospects, 1996-2002 (Box 40, Folder 7-8)
        - Grant requests to NWHN, 1982-87 (Box 40, Folder 9)
        - Granting organizations
          - Action, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 10)
          - American Foundation for AIDS Research, 1988-93, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 11)
          - ARCA, 1977-85 (Box 40, Folder 12)
          - Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, 1998-2001 (Box 40, Folder 13)
          - Buehler Family Fund, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 14)
          - Breast Cancer Fund, 1996-99 (Box 40, Folder 15)
          - Chicago Resource Center, 1987-91 (Box 40, Folder 16)
          - David and Lucile Packard Foundation, 1995-99 (Box 41, Folder 1)
          - eGrants.org, 2000-02 (Box 41, Folder 2)
          - Ericsson Internet Community Award, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 3)
          - Fund for Southern Communities, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 4)
          - Funding Exchange, 1992-95 (Box 41, Folder 5)
          - Harmony Women's Fund, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 6)
          - Gaea Foundation, 1996-2004 (Box 41, Folder 7)
          - Grubb Pharmacy, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 8)
          - Heinz Family Foundation, 1997-99 (Box 41, Folder 9)
          - Huber Foundation, 1999-2000 (Box 41, Folder 10)
          - J.M. Foundation, 1978-85 (Box 41, Folder 11)
          - Jenifer Altman Foundation, 1995-97 (Box 41, Folder 12)
          - Jessie Smith Noyes Foundation, 1983-86 (Box 41, Folder 13)
          - Joyce Foundation, 1978-83 (Box 41, Folder 14)
          - Kaiser Family Foundation, 1992-97 (Box 41, Folder 15)
          - Levi Strauss Foundation,1979-82 (Box 41, Folder 16)
          - MacDonald's Corporation, 1978-79 (Box 41, Folder 17)
          - Mary Reynolds Babcock Foundation, 1990-96 (Box 41, Folder 18)
          - Meyer Foundation, 2001 (Box 41, Folder 19)
          - Ms. Foundation for Women, 1992-99 (Box 41, Folder 20)
          - National Council of Churches, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 21)
          - National Community Funds, 1988-90 (Box 41, Folder 22)
          - National Institute of Education, 1978-79 (Box 41, Folder 23)
          - Open Society Institute, 1997-2000 (Box 41, Folder 24)
          - Ottinger Foundation, 1990-92 (Box 42, Folder 1)
          - Partnership for Democracy, 1990-92 (Box 42, Folder 2)
          - Playboy Foundation, 1980-85 (Box 42, Folder 3)
          - Philip M. Stern Family Fund, 1975-83 (Box 42, Folder 4)
          - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 1988-99 (Box 42, Folder 5-7)
          - Ruth Mott Fund, 1990-91 (Box 42, Folder 8)
          - Scherman Foundation, 1979-83 (Box 42, Folder 9)
          - Schott Foundation, 1994-95 (Box 42, Folder 10)
          - Shalan Foundation, 1981-82 (Box 42, Folder 11)
          - Sister Fund, 2000-01 (Box 42, Folder 12)
          - Stewart R. Mott Charitable Trust, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 13)
          - Summit Charitable Foundation, 1995-2002 (Box 42, Folder 14)
          - Support Center, 1977-78 (Box 42, Folder 15)
          - Turner Foundation, 2001-02 (Box 43, Folder 1)
          - Walton Jones Foundation, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 2)
          - W.K. Kellogg Foundation, 1992-98 (Box 43, Folder 3)
          - Windom Fund, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 4)
          - Miscellaneous, 1978-2002 (Box 43, Folder 5-7)
        - Fundraising reports to the board, 1977-84 (Box 43, Folder 6)
        - Guidelines, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 7)
        - Projects
          - Action Project (rural women's health), n.d. (Box 43, Folder 8)
          - AIDS, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 9)
          - Anti-Smoking project, 1984-85 (Box 43, Folder 10)
          - Appalachian Pathways, 1980-81 (Box 44, Folder 1)
          - Black Women's Health Project (Box 44)
            [see SERIES IX. PROJECTS, PRGRAMS, AND REFORM EFFORTS- Black Women's Health Project - Financial]
          - Cervical Cap Project and "Phony" Abortion Clinics, 1986-87 (Box 44, Folder 2)
          - Clearinghouse projects, 1995-2001 (Box 44, Folder 3)
          - Dalkon Shield International Information Project (Box 44, Folder 4)
          - Depo-Provera Emergency Grant, 1979-83 (Box 44, Folder 5)
          - DES Project and DES Community Outreach and Education Project, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 6)
          - Environmental Health Project, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 7)
          - FDA's Impact on Family Health: A Technical Assistance Project, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 8)
          - General support proposals, 1985-2005 (Box 44, Folder 9-12)
          - Health Advocacy in Rural America, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 1)
          - Health Workers for Peace Project, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - Helping Mothers and their Newborns: A Critique of FDA Policy as It Affects Maternal and Child Health, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 3)
          - Influencing Health Policy: A Proposal to Educate the Nation's Health Policy makers and to make the Network financially self-sufficient at the same time, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 4)
          - Internship funding, 1997-99 (Box 45, Folder 5)
          - Midlife and Older Women's Project, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 6)
          - Our Bodies, Ourselves, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 7)
          - Putting Women First: The FDA and Reproductive Health Technology, 1996 (Box 45, Folder 8)
          - Reproductive rights projects, 1988-89 (Box 45, Folder 9)
          - "Resource Guide for Women's Environmental Health," 1987 (Box 45, Folder 10)
          - Rural Women and Alcoholism Prevention Project, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 11)
          - Sterilization Abuse Project, 1978-79 (Box 45, Folder 12)
          - Survey of American Women and Women's Health Care Providers on Contraceptive Research Priorities, 1978-79 (Box 45, Folder 13)
          - Volunteers for Women's Health Advocacy, 1979-80 (Box 45, Folder 14)
          - Women to Women Project, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 15)
          - Women's Health and the Environment Booklet, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 16)
          - Women's Health Information Service, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 17)
          - Miscellaneous, 1985-86 (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Reports and miscellaneous correspondence, 1977-2003 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Proposals, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Investments, 1981-83 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - List rental, 1984-85 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous fundraisers
        - Co-op America, 1986-88 (Box 46, Folder 6)
        - Donor luncheon, Boston, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - GiveForChange (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Maine fundraiser, 1980-81 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - T-shirt fundraiser, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - 10th Anniversary of Our Bodies, Ourselves, 1979-80 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Trips and meetings: New York, 1978-79 (Box 46, Folder 12-13)
    - Loans
      - Agreement form, 1979 (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - Crisis funding, 1985-88 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - Payable, 1979-86 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Organizations
      - Fundraising in the Public Interest, 1978-79 (Box 46, Folder 17)
      - Independent Sector, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 18)
      - Maryland Association of Nonprofit Organizations:
        - Fundraising in Times of Crisis, 2003 (Box 46, Folder 19)
        - The Ask: The Art and skill of Getting to YES!, 2004 (Box 46, Folder 20)
      - National Committee for Responsive Philanthropy, 1979 (Box 46, Folder 21)
      - National Information Bureau, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 22)
      - National Society of Fundraising Executives, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 23)
      - National Network of Women's Funds, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 24)
      - Network of Change Oriented Foundations, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 25)
      - Support Center of Washington, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Women and Foundations/Corporate Philanthropy, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Stolen checks, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Tax materials
      - Exemptions for charities, 1977-88 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Returns, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 6)
- SERIES VI. PUBLICATIONS AND REPORTS, 1976-2005
  Along with the Network's programs and projects, the publication of its Newsletter and subject related booklets, packets, fact sheets, and resource guides are major ways the organization carries out its mission. This series is divided into three subseries: Correspondence, Publications by NWHN and P ublications and reports written on behalf of the NWHN.
  The Correspondence subseries relates to publication orders, subscription renewals, distribution and shipping, comments, and complaints. It is arranged chronologically.
  Publications by the NWHN contains two sections: the first contains general publications and the second the Network's newsletter. The first is arranged alphabetically by title and contains a wide variety of outreach publications along with some correspondence related to production, advertising, and marketing. Subjects include abortion, AIDS, cancer, Dalkon Shield, Depo-Provera, DES, diabetes, hormone replacement, maternal health, national health plan, mammograms, sterilization, tampons and toxic shock syndrome, and environmental health. There are nine numbered Resource Guides [Breast Cancer, Hysterectomy, Menopause, Maternal Health and Childbirth, DES, Self Help, Abortion, and Sterilization]. The Network's newsletters (Network News, 1976-2003, and Women's Health Activist, 2004-2005) and related materials are located in the second section. Included are issues of the newsletters along with background materials; notes; original typed copies of issues; copyright requests; correspondence; subject files; photographs and graphics; documentation of plans, procedures and processes; review requests; and subscription exchange material.
  Publications and reports written on behalf of the NWHN contains eight reports. There is one authored by Belita Cowan, but most were the result of student research at Brown University. Topics include the health of incarcerated women, hepatitis, miscarriage, still birth and neonatal death, breast implants, tamoxifen, uterine cancer, and women's health care.
  - Correspondence, 1980-92 (Box 48, Folder 1-3)
  - Published by NWHN
    [see also SERIES IX. PROJECTS, PROGRAMS, AND REFORM EFFORTS- Black Women's Health Project - Publications]
    - Abortion Rights: Organizers Kit, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - "Abortion Then and Now: Creative Responses to Restricted Access"
      - Permissions, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Publicity, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Published booklet, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Advice for Life: A Woman's Guide to AIDS Risks and Prevention by Chris Norwood, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Breast Cancer Materials, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - "The Dalkon Shield," 1985
      - English (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - French (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - Spanish (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - "Depo-Provera" (the Depo-Provera Debate), 1983, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - "Diabetes and Women," n.d. (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Fact sheets, 1995-99, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "Get the Facts," 1997 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - "Hearts, Bones, Hot Flashes, and Hormones," 1988-89 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "How Safe Is Safe," 1982 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - "Keeping Healthy After HIV/AIDS Diagnosis: A Women's Guide To HIV Disease And Health Care," n.d. (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - "National Health Plan: Principles for a National Health Plan," n.d. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - "Patterns for Change," 1981 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - "Perspectives"
      - Cervical cancer and pap smears, 1999-2001 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Mammograms, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Review Committee, 200-2002 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Timing of surgery, 2000-2002 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Workfile, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 1999, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Research to Improve Women's Health: An Agenda for Equity, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Resource guides, 1980
      - Overview, form letters, advertising and production outlines, 1980-81, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Breast Cancer (#1) (Box 50)
      - Hysterectomy (#2) (Box 50)
      - Menopause (#3) (Box 50)
      - Maternal Health and Childbirth (#4) (Box 50)
      - Birth Control (#5) (Box 50)
      - DES (#6) (Box 50)
      - Self Help (#7 (Box 50)
      - Abortion (#8) (Box 50)
      - Sterilization (#9) (Box 50)
    - "Sterilization Abuse: What It Is and How It Can be Controlled," 1981 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Taking Hormones and Women's Health: Choices, Risks, and Benefits
      - Advertising and marketing, 1995-2002 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Published booklet, 1989-2000 (Box 51, Folder 2-3)
      - Reviews and reviewers, 1989-2002 (Box 51, Folder 4-5)
      - Translations, 1989-92 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - "Tampons and Toxic Shock Syndrome: A Report by the National Women's Health Network," 1983 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - "Truth About Hormone Replacement Therapy," 2001 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - "Turning Things Around: A Women's Occupational and Environmental Health Resource Guide," 1990 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - "Volunteers for Women's Health Advocacy," 1982 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - "Women, AIDS and Public Health Policies: A National Women's Health Network Report," 1990 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - "Women and HIV/AIDS," 2001 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Women and Cancer Conference (Reports), 1986 (Box 52)
      [see SERIES X. PROJECTS, PROGRAMS AND REFORM EFFORTS - Breast Cancer Campaign - Conferences]
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-86, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Newsletters
      - Issues (Box 52)
        - Network News (Box 52)
          - 1976-89 (Box 53, Folder 1-14)
          - 1990-2003 (Box 54, Folder 1-14)
        - Women's Health Activist, 2004-05, 2013 (Box 54, Folder 15)
      - Background material, notes, and original typed copies
        - 1982-85 (Box 55, Folder 1-9)
        - 1989-2002 (Box 56, Folder 1-19)
        - 2003-05 (Box 57, Folder 1-11)
      - Copyright requests, 1997-2005 (Box 58, Folder 1-3)
      - Correspondence
        - Form letters, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous, 1981-2003 (Box 58, Folder 5-7)
      - Future articles (subject files)
        - Peace/disarmament, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 8)
        - Who's who in congress, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 9)
        - Health law and legislation/Federal health policy, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 10)
      - Maternal and child health, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      - Drugs and substance abuse, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 12)
      - International, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 13)
      - News from around the country, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 14)
      - Names in the news, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-85, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Newsbriefs possibilities, 1982-83 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Photographs and graphics, 1982-85, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Plans, procedures. and process, 1983-2000 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Requests for items to review, 1983-84, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Resources sections, 1982, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Subscription exchange, 1983 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985-88, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Publications and reports written on behalf of the NWHN
    - "Abortion," 1998 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - "Abortion: A Holistic Account," 2001 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - "Access to Childbirth Options," 2001 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - "Adolescent Women's Sexual and Reproductive Health," 2001 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - "Chronic Vulvar Pain," 1998 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - "Development of the Women's Health Movement 1970-97: Health Activists Challenge the System," 1997 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - "The Female Orgasm: Women Speak on How It Works, Why It Is Important, And How To Have One," 1998 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - "Health Insurance: Why We Need It, Who Does Not Have It, And How We Can Get It," 1998 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Health of Incarcerated Women, 1997 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - "Hepatitis and the Health of Women: a Guide to Medicine, Social Experience, and Politics in the U.S.," 2001 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - "Loss Happens to Us: Demystifying and Speaking Up About the Experience of Miscarriage, Stillbirth and Neonatal Death, 2001 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - "Saline Breast Implants", 2001 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Scoliosis, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Tamoxifen and the Breast Cancer Prevention Trial, 1998 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - "Uterine Cancer: An Exploration of Epidemiology, Diagnosis, Treatment and Experience," 1997 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - "Women's Health Care: Resources, Writings, Bibliographies" by Belita Cowan, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 5)
- SERIES VII. CORRESPONDENCE, 1977-2006
  For the most part this series generally reflects the Network's original arrangement. It is divided into four subseries: S taff, Interns and volunteers, Chronological files, and Subjects. The first two subseries are arranged alphabetically by individual. In the Staff subseries Belita Cowan (executive director), April Pace (program director), and Sybil Schainwald (Chair of the Board) have the largest amount of correspondence. The Interns and Volunteer correspondence consists mostly of letters in response to requests for information and the sending out of printed material and publications. The Chronological files contains a wide range of letters to and from Network personnel and reflect general Network business. Subjects consists of correspondence with the American Public Health Association, what the NWHN staff categorized as "crazy mail," "golden letters," and "endorsements." The "endorsement" files contain letters on a variety of topics, many of which are endorsements for NWHN programs. In addition there are Freedom of Information requests, letters of support, correspondence with members of the U.S. Congress and Administration, a discussion with the National Women's Health Center Foundation regarding its name, and requests for information (cervical cap, Depo-Provera, and miscellaneous). The NWHN was featured on the Geraldo Show in January 1988 and the Phil Donahue Show on March 7, 1985 and the resulting mail is also included here.
  - Staff
    - Baker, Beverly (executive director), 1992-96 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Burns, Mary (office manager), 1979 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Clift, Elayne (program director), 1980 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Cowan, Belita (executive director)
      - 1977-79 (Box 62, Folder 4-9)
      - 1980-83 (Box 63, Folder 1-2)